▍2026 美网 男单决赛
兹维列夫 6-3 7-6² 5-7 6-2 谢尔顿 · 赛后场上采访
And it is now time to invite our champion
下面有请我们的冠军
to the stage, Alexander Zverev.
登台 亚历山大·兹维列夫
Sasha, you've waited a little bit for this one.
萨沙 这一座你等了不少时候
This moment and the microphone,
这一刻和这支话筒
it's all yours.
都交给你了
Yeah.
好
Very first thing I want to start off
我想先从一个人说起
with with Ben.
就是谢尔顿
Ben, you're you're an incredible player,
谢尔顿 你是个了不起的球员
incredible person.
也是个了不起的人
This was your first Grand Slam final,
这是你第一次打大满贯决赛
but I already told you you're going
但我已经跟你说过
to be back here many many more times.
你还会站上来很多很多次
And I if I would have to bet all my money
要是让我押上所有身家
on it, I I would bet
我敢赌
that you would lift this trophy one day.
你总有一天会举起这座奖杯
Then I I want to thank I don't want
然后我想谢谢 不对
to thank I want
不是谢谢 我是想
to wish a congratul Sorry I can't talk.
说声恭 抱歉我说不出话了
We played for four hours.
我们打了四个小时
I want to say well done to to Ben's team
我想对谢尔顿的团队说声漂亮
to Brian to everybody who's there.
布莱恩 还有那边的每一个人
To pops I think to mom and sister
还有他爸爸 妈妈和姐姐
as well.
也一样
I think everybody is just as important
我觉得那边的每一个人
over there as they are on this side
和球场这一边的人
of the court.
一样重要
I know it's a it's exactly what what
我知道那正是
my family is and that's why I'm so happy
我家的样子 所以我特别高兴
to see you guys in in these kind of finals.
看到你们站在这样的决赛里
I'm so happy
我特别高兴
to see you guys win masters events
看到你们赢下大师赛
and big tournaments because I know
和那些大赛 因为我知道
that it's a family affair.
这是一家人的事
And everybody is pulling
所有人都朝着同一个方向
on the same strings to be successful.
一起使劲
So, congratulations to you, congratulations
所以恭喜你 也恭喜
to mom, to sister, to everyone who is there
妈妈 姐姐 在场的每一个人
because you guys really deserve it.
你们真的配得上
Trinity, I thought you have a game today.
特里尼蒂 我以为你今天有比赛
No.
没有吗？
Well done to you as well.
你也很棒
You're you're the lucky charm.
你就是那个幸运符
So, I'm I'm happy.
所以我很开心
Not Not today, but usually then I want
今天不算 平时是
to thank my team.
然后我想谢谢我的团队
We went we went 30 years
我们走了三十年
without winning a grand slam title
没拿到一个大满贯
and now we won two in a span of 3 months.
现在三个月里拿了两个
So it's I think I think God
所以我想 老天
has seen how hard we worked,
看见了我们有多拼
how much we suffered,
吃了多少苦
how much pain we went
受了多少罪
through and I think 2026
我觉得 2026 年
is the outcome of all the years
是前面那些年
that that happened before.
攒出来的结果
So thank you guys.
谢谢你们
You guys are absolutely amazing.
你们太了不起了
and couldn't couldn't be here
没有你们
without you guys.
我不可能站在这里
Then I want
然后
to thank actually one more person who's
我还想谢一个人
never actually watching my matches
这个人从来不看我的比赛
but is the most important person
却是最重要的那一个
in my tennis life and in my life in general
在我的网球里 也在我的人生里
because when your four-year-old
因为当你四岁的儿子
son gets diagnosed with diabetes
被诊断出糖尿病
and doctors in the office tell you
诊室里的医生告诉你
that life and sports will be very very limited
这孩子的生活和运动
for that child.
都会非常非常受限
It takes a very very strong mother
得是一位非常坚强的母亲
to walk out of those offices
才能走出那间诊室
and to say my son my my son
然后说 我儿子
will be whatever he wants to be.
他想成为什么就成为什么
If he wants to be a tennis player,
他想打网球
he'll be a tennis player.
他就去打网球
If he wants to do something else,
他想做别的事
he do something else.
那就去做别的事
But this illness will not define us.
但这个病定义不了我们
And I'm happy that that we work
我很高兴
through it and we're doing things
我们一路扛了过来
that we're doing right now.
才有了今天这些
And my my mother is my mother
我的母亲
is the most important
是最重要的那个人
and the strongest person I know
也是我见过最坚强的人
because it takes
因为这件事
an unbelievably strong woman
得是个坚强到难以想象的女人
to to do what she did.
才做得到她做过的事
So thanks to her as well.
所以也谢谢她
Then I want to thank everyone
然后我想谢谢
who worked in this tournament this year.
今年为这项赛事工作的每个人
And I am sorry that I was the reason
很抱歉是因为我
that a lot of you guys went to bed
你们很多人才要
at 4, 5 a.m.
凌晨四五点才上床
this year.
就在今年
I was two points away from losing
我差两分就输掉了
in the first round.
第一轮那场球
I'm very happy that I won that match
我很庆幸赢下了那场
because it would have been a different
否则今天的结果
outcome otherwise.
就完全不一样了
And I want to thank the the ball boys.
我想谢谢球童
I want to thank the the people
想谢谢那些
that were behind the scenes.
在幕后忙的人
I want to thank the drivers.
想谢谢司机
I want to thank everyone
想谢谢
who works in the restaurant.
餐厅里工作的每一位
Everybody
所有
who stayed up late just for us.
为我们熬夜的人
And it's it's not it it's really appreciated
这些大家真的都看在眼里
by everyone and I want to thank them
每个人都心存感激
as well.
也谢谢他们
Then Eric, first year
还有埃里克 第一年
as a tourn director.
做赛事总监
So, congratulations to you
恭喜你
for putting up such an amazing event.
办出这么好的一届
I'm sorry it's the wrong winner
抱歉今年这个冠军归了我
this this year but I yeah I I did my job
但我只是做了自己的本职
but thank you very much and you
总之非常感谢
did amazing Craig for those of you
你做得很好 然后是克雷格
that you don't know Craig Tiley
可能有人不认识克雷格·蒂利
has been the tournament director
过去二十五年
in the Australian Open for the past 25 years
他一直是澳网的赛事总监
and he decided to move to New York.
然后他决定搬来纽约
Um,
嗯
which we as players were not very happy
我们这些球员其实不太乐意
about because he made
因为正是他
the Australian Open the best tournament
把澳网办成了
in the world.
世界上最好的赛事
But from now on, I think the US Open
但从今往后 我觉得美网
will probably be the best tournament
大概会变成
in the world since you're here.
世界上最好的 因为你来了
So, thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you for moving here.
谢谢你搬过来
Thank you for being here.
谢谢你在这儿
Move back to Australia for like 3 months
要不回澳大利亚待三个月
and then come back end of January.
一月底再回来
That would be great.
那就太好了
But no, it's it's really I think the best hire
说真的 我觉得这是
that the USTA could have done
美网协会最成功的一次引进
and well done for putting up
第一年就办出
such an amazing event the first year.
这么棒的一届 干得漂亮
Then last but not least, the crowds.
最后同样重要的 是观众
Yeah, I know that that today 99.9%
我知道今天 99.9% 的人
of the player the people wanted Ben to win.
都希望谢尔顿赢
So I'm very sorry first of all, but second it
首先很抱歉 其次
was an an incredible atmosphere to play in.
在这样的氛围里打球太棒了
Even though I know
虽然我知道
that the crowd was against me,
全场都不站在我这边
the crowd was always incredibly fair
但观众始终非常公道
and we as players, we appreciate it.
我们球员很感激这一点
You guys brought the energy,
你们带来了能量
you guys brought the noise,
带来了声浪
and we really thank you guys for that.
真的谢谢你们
I think I talked enough.
我觉得我说得够多了
So, thank you and see you next year.
谢谢大家 明年见
You're not done yet, Sasha.
还没完呢 萨沙